

# Dvid Silva

/San Francisco, Ca

+1 415 377 6450

contacto@dvidsilva.com @dvidsilva linkedin.com/in/dvidsilva I've been working as a full stack for four years now, in a broad variety of companies, trying to learn something new very often, look for new solutions to every challenge, research and find the most appropriate way to accomplish.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Cytelsat | Developer

Bogotá Col — february - august 2013

The company developed a tool in Java that would gather information about the usage of computers in classrooms, my task was to compile this data in mysql/php from every room and send it to our servers where the interested would see reports in the usage.

During the time here I used AngularJS, MorrisJs, Sass, PHP, Mysql, Yii, ZendLoader, using the TDD methodology.

## tuta.co | CTO

Bogotá Col — august 2012 january 2013

In tuta I was a lone developer, in charge of maintaining the platform, adding new features and functionalities requested by our users and making sure all the servers are deployed in the right way. We would iterate really fast, using the information gathered from analytics and the designers advice.

During this time I used Jquery, Php, MySql, Sass, Azure, YouTubeApi, FbOauth

## **Bweb SAS | developer**

Bogota october 2011, february 2012

Bweb is a software agency, the product I was working on is a system that receives the sales and performance of employees and gives them points that they can redeem for prizes; we had several clients, white labeled, so my job was to customize the platform for different clients according to the designs given, and the specific reports they wanted to see; making sure that all was integrated, since they used a single database.

I was working here with Php/Mysql, it was heavier in the back end.

## Lumni | Junior developer

Bogota february 2011

I was working in the data analyst department which consisted on economist and industrial engineers; Lumni loans money to students that they pay after they graduate with a percentage of their salary if they're working, so it is really important to design and implement algorithms that would ensure the selected applicants would not drop out of school and will graduate with honors and be able to find jobs. My role was to implement the algorithms designed by the team in the platform, from capturing the answers of the applicants to processing them.

I was working here in php/mysql heavier in the back end, using the SCRUM methodology.

## Auditor400 | Junior developer

Bogota august 2009 - january 2011

This was my first job as a developer, I had the chance to sit with senior developers who would teach me about what they were doing so I could assist them in coding, testing or documenting. Before every session of work everything would be discussed to make sure everybody understood, and gave their opinion.

We worked here with .net, sqlserver, mysql, php and python, we would use the language that would be a better fit for the client requirements.

## ADDITIONAL PROJECTS

#### Fotokio.com 2012

Imgur clone with rails and postgresql

## Favey.com 2012

Like ask.fm with images and effects with synatra and mongoDb

#### MemeGusta.com.co 2011

Funny images and memes sharing site with php/mysql

## **Sites for Clients** 2010 - 2013

koshersubway.net - yayapromo.com - incersa.com - mauriciovidal.net serviciochevrolet.com.ec - <a href="http://questioning.herokuapp.com/">http://questioning.herokuapp.com/</a> - consultoriaeconomicayempresarial.co +many more

# Additional Acomplishments 2010 - 2013

I have won several of the hackatons and contests on which I have participated, being AngelHack summer 2013 the most representative of all, sponzorme.com - <a href="http://gifthack.herokuapp.com/">http://gifthack.herokuapp.com/</a> - dvidsilva.github.io/blackorwhite - <a href="http://hojavirtual.herokuapp.com/">http://hojavirtual.herokuapp.com/</a> - dvidsilva.github.io/udressme - <a href="http://reportaco.herokuapp.com/reportes">http://reportaco.herokuapp.com/reportes</a> - <a href="http://investico.herokuapp.com/">http://investico.herokuapp.com/</a> - <a href="http://investico.herokuapp.com/">http:

## **EDUCATION**

## **Beth-Shalom High School**

High School 2005

## Lasalle College Bogotá

Graphic and multimedia design 2006-2007

## Agbo

Objective C Basics 2013

## **EshHaTorah**

Jewish culture, Jerusalem, 2007-2008

## **SKILLS**

- Web Software design
- Agile development in Php or Ruby, using Sql or NoSql engines
- Front end development, using Html5, Css3, Jquery and Angular
- Server and Cdn implementation and maintenance